<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<main>
  <PageData>
	<MainHeading><![CDATA[<b>14 SMART GRIDS</b>]]></MainHeading>
    <SubHeading><![CDATA[<b>14.1 Introduction</b>]]></SubHeading>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[A smart grid is an electricity network based on digital technology that is used to supply electricity to consumers via two-way digital communication. This system allows for monitoring, analysis, control and communication within the supply chain to help improve efficiency, reduce energy consumption and cost and maximize the transparency and reliability of the energy supply chain. In traditional electric grid, energy generation is done in centralized power plants. Energy distribution is one directional from the power plant to the homes or industries. The monitoring and restoration of grid is done manually. The communication is uni-directional. The smart grid was introduced with the aim of overcoming the weaknesses of conventional electrical grids by using smart net meters. Many government institutions around the world have been encouraging the use of smart grids for their potential to control and deal with global warming, emergency resilience and energy independence scenarios.]]></pText>
    </PageText>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[Smart grids achieve high reliability in power streams. It is a cyber-physical system equipped with sustainable models of energy production, distribution and usage. Smart grid is conceptualized as a planned nationwide network that uses information technology to deliver electricity efficiently, reliably and securely. Smart grid is also named as electricity with a brain or the energy Internet or electronet. Smart grid is a modernized grid that enables bidirectional flow of energy and uses two-way communication and control capabilities that will lead to an array of new functionalities and applications]]></pText>
    </PageText>
      <span class="PageVideoClass" id="Video_BTNID" url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KgVFJnmJvKk" headername="Video">
    <span class="PageAudioClass" id="Audio_BTNID" url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KgVFJnmJvKk" headername="Audio"></span>


  
  </PageData>
</main>