<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<main>
  <PageData>
	<MainHeading><![CDATA[]]></MainHeading>
    <SubHeading><![CDATA[<b>14.6 Smart Homes</b>]]></SubHeading>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[Smart homes use emerging smart grid technologies to save energy, seek the lowest rates and contribute to the smooth and efficient functioning of electric grid. The interactive relationship between the grid operators, utilities and consumer helps in proper functioning of smart grid technologies. Computerized controls in smart homes help to minimize energy use at times when the power grid is under stress from high demand or even to shift some of their power use to times when power is available at a lower cost, i.e. from on-peak hours to off-peak hours. Smart home depends on several components like smart meters, home energy management systems, smart appliances and home power generation.]]></pText>
    </PageText>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Smart meters:</b> Smart meters provide the smart grid interface between consumer and the energy service provider. These meters operate digitally. Smart meters allow for automated and complex transfers of information between consumer-end and the energy service provider. It helps to reduce the energy costs of the consumers and provides information about usage of electricity in different service areas to the energy service providers.]]></pText>
    </PageText>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Home energy management systems:</b> It allows consumers to track energy usage in detail to better save energy. Energy management systems allow consumers to monitor real-time information and price from the energy service provider. It provides settings to automatically use power when prices are lowest. The peak demand rates can be avoided using home energy management system. Further, it helps to balance the energy load in different area and also prevents blackouts. In return, the service provider may chose to provide financial incentives.]]></pText>
    </PageText>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Smart appliances:</b> These appliances are automated and robust in nature. It responds to signals from the energy service provider to avoid energy usage during times of peak-demand. For example an appliance may turn off automatically for few hours during peak hours to save energy. It can include consumer controls to override the automated controls. By overriding, the consumer can consume energy as per their requirements, while paying minimum is not ensured.]]></pText>
    </PageText>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Home power generation:</b> Power generation system at consumer end is one of the features of smart homes. Smart homes can have rooftop solar electric systems, small wind turbines or small hydropower systems. Home fuel cell systems that produce heat and power from natural gas can also be included in smart homes. Surplus energy generated by the home power generation systems can be fed back into the grid.]]></pText>
    </PageText>
  
  </PageData>
</main>