<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<main>
  <PageData>
	<MainHeading><![CDATA[]]></MainHeading>
  <SubHeading><![CDATA[14.2 Characteristics of Smart Grid]]></SubHeading>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Enables active participation by consumers—</b> Consumer choices and increased interaction with the grid bring tangible benefits to both the grid and the environment, while reducing the cost of delivered electricity. The real-time monitoring of consumption, control of smart appliances, building automation and real-time pricing are some important characteristics of smart grid]]></pText>
    </PageText>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Enables new products, services and markets —</b> The grid’s open-access market reveals waste and inefficiency and helps drive them out of the system while offering new consumer choices such as green power products and a new generation of electric vehicles. Reduced transmission congestion also leads to more efficient electricity markets.]]></pText>
    </PageText>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Provides power quality for the digital economy —</b> Digital-grade power quality for  those who need it avoids production and productivity losses, especially in digital-device environments. Load forecasting is also possible with smart grids.]]></pText>
    </PageText>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Optimizes asset utilization and operates efficiently —</b> Desired functionality at  minimum cost guides operations and allows fuller utilization of assets. More targeted and efficient grid maintenance programs result in fewer equipment failures and safer operations.]]></pText>
    </PageText>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Anticipates and responds to system disturbances (self-heals) —</b> The smart grid will perform continuous self-assessments to detect, analyze, respond to and as needed, restore grid components or network sections.]]></pText>
    </PageText>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<b>Operates resiliently against attack and natural disaster —</b> The grid deters or withstands physical or cyber attack and improves public safety.]]></pText>
    </PageText>
    <PageText>
      <pText><![CDATA[<p></p>]]></pText>
    </PageText>
                
  </PageData>
</main>